Roger Steve Ruiz

+18045392255 <u>hi@rog.gr</u> <u>http://rog.gr</u> Brooklyn, NY

Profile

I'm a web developer with over five years experience building websites, interfaces, & products. From concept to execution, I'm interested in all aspects of user experience, interface design, & code optimizations. I've worked with JetBlue, Caesars Casinos, WellPoint, Chipotle, Condé Nast, & other clients. I have a proven background in successfully handling all aspects of web development.

Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, CONDÉ NAST; NEW YORK, NY - 2013 - PRESENT

Building & maintaining a video streaming website along with nine other engineers.

Practicing SCRUM along with continuous integration & daily deployments to production.

Routine daily interactions with the director of product design. Working in a completely

Rails 4 development environment. Working remotely four to five times per month.

SENIOR DEVELOPER, ROKKAN; NEW YORK, NY - 2011 - 2013

Worked collaboratively with UI & UX designers to execute websites for clients. Involved in client presentations and internal meetings throughout the process. Lead developer on JetBlue, Chipotle, & WellPoint projects. Gave talks and trained coworkers on new topics.

PREPRESS MANAGER AND WEB DESIGNER, TEKWELD; FARMINGDALE, NY - 2007 - 2011

Handled every aspect of delivering files to the press operator of an HP Indigo 4500.

Devised algorithms to most efficiently utilize finite printing materials. Trained employees on key responsibilities of the job with video & printed material. Maintained company website, created custom web forms and other small-scale websites, managed email marketing campaigns and HTML email templates.

Education

Nassau Community College 2007 – A.A.S. Digital Art & Printing

Skills

HTML, CSS, Sass, Javascript, jQuery, Ember, Rails, Backbone, AMD, TDD, NodeJS, Grunt, Bash, Zsh, Git, SVN, /r[egx]{2,}p?/i, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

References available upon request